

# **Abel Mitiku**

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia abelmgetnet@gmail.com



**Portfolio** 



<u>GitHub</u>



Linkedin



**Medium** 

## **About Me**

I am a Junior Machine Learning/AI Engineer with a software engineering background. Experience utilizing tools like Pandas, Numpy, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Scikitlearn, Seaborn, and Matplotlib. I have experience in data visualization, preprocessing, feature engineering, and developing an end-to-end machine learning pipeline for artificial intelligence, business and other areas.

#### **Skills & Proficiencies**

- · Python, Java, Dart
- AWS
- MySQL, PostgreSQL
- DBT. Airflow
- · Git, DVC, MLflow, Docker
- Numpy, Pandas
- · PyTorch, TensorFlow
- CML, Travis CI
- Tableau
- · Bash, Zsh, shell
- Flutter, Kotlin
- HTML, CSS, ReactJS

## **Educational Background**

### **Addis Ababa University**

BSc in Electrical & Computer Engineering 2016 - 2021

## **Relevant Courses**

- 00P, Computer Architecture
- MATLAB
- C++, JAVA
- VHDL, Verilog
- Applied Mathematics I III
- · Probability and statistics
- EMFs, Modern Physics
- Economics

#### 10 Academy

Data Engineering and Machine Learning Engineering Apr 2022 - Jul 2022

## **Relevant Courses**

A Project-based Intensive training where I got to work on 12 projects that helped me develop the following skill-sets:

- Machine Learning (AI) Pipeline Development
- Data Engineering Principles and Large Scale Implementations
- Web3.0 Dapp Development
- · Statistical Reasoning
- A/B Testing/Business Analysis
- Causal Inference
- Speech recognition
- Data warehouse, Kafka, Airflow

## **Projects**

## **Telecom User Data Analytics**

This project was to analyze customer behavior in terms of their engagement, experience, and satisfaction for a telecom company and suggest if the company is worthy of buying or selling.

# Breast Cancer Diagnosis using causal inference

This project focuses on using causal inference to answer causal questions related to breast cancer cases. It uses tabular data with features about different individuals' cell samples and predicts whether a person has cancer or not using AI.

## Ethereum Blockchain (Crypto) Smart Contract

Made a mobile App that facilitates when an employer pays an employee, for being present in a certain geographic area for a certain duration. The employee's phone sends its GPS location to a smart contract at a certain interval. Based on the pre-agreed contract codified in an Ethereum smart contract, a cryptocurrency payment is executed when all the agreed conditions are met.

# Work Experience

Web/App Developer GuzoGo Mar 2022 - Present

- Understand client requirements and how they translate in application features
- Ability to program in at least one programming language such as C#, Java (J2EE).
- · Functional Vs Non-Functional Testing
- · Proficient in React, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.
- · Proficient in MySQL, and PostgreSQL.

#### BackEnd Dev

Advanced Engineering P.L.C Dec 2021 - Feb 2022

- Using specialist tools to extract the data needed
- Responding to data-related queries and keeping track of these
- Setting up processes and systems to make working with data more efficient

Hardware and Software Integration Addis Ababa Institute Of Technology, Intern Aug 2021 - Oct 2021

- Aided in the development of each transaction's database and the analysis of each transaction's data.
- Contributed to the hardware development for the WiFi module's integration on the main board.
- Construct a wireless module interface-capable mobile payment system.